okay number two asks convert the
following compound in condensed notation
into the appropriate line notation so
now we're going the other way we're
taking our condensed notation and we're
expanding that into line notation we
start with ch3 so we have a methyl group
and then that is going to connect to co
So Co is our carbonal group so here is
our methyl and then we have our carbonal
next is going to be ch ch looking ahead
a little bit we know that we have a
carbon and then that is going to be
bound to just one hydrogen and then
another carbon that is also bound to
just one hydrogen but if both of these
carbons are just bound to one hydrogen
that means that there must be a double
bond between them because all these
carbons have to have four bonds and so
the way we get ch ch is by making a pi
Bond there between those carbons after
chch we have ch2 so that's just a
regular ch2